Sahil Chawla

UX/UI DESIGNER

LINKEDIN | MEDIUM | BEHANCE | PORTFOLIO

Gurugram +91- 9034875758 Approach.sahil@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

With around 3.5 years of experience as a UX designer, I have successfully worked on product journeys from conceptualisation to feature launch. Core strengths are in user research, data-driven design solutions supported by skills in product strategy, wireframing, prototyping, user interviews and A/B testing. Additionally, my 4 years of experience in architecture have honed my ability to align with revenue growth.

EXPERIENCE

Adani Digital Labs (Trainman, 13M+ Downloads), Gurgaon – Senior UX designer

Feb 2022 - Present

- Revamped post-payment user flow by performing competitor analysis, card sorting, user interviews leading to a 15% reduction in drop rates.
- Created a chatbot flow, conducted user interviews, created information architecture, flow charts, did A/B testing, prioritized user issues by card sorting resulting in a 30-40% decrease in support calls.
- Designed "Trip Assurance" and "Alternate Confirm seats" pioneer features. Performed competitor analysis, did primary and secondary research. Developed Journey maps, prototypes, Increased company revenue by 15% through this feature.
- Designed 'Free Cancellation scheme', resulting in a 12% to 18% increase in conversion. Added Gamification for referral program
- Improved booking funnel user experience by performing competitor analysis, heat map analysis, design reiteration and user interviews.

Placco Lumen travel Pvt limited, New delhi - UX Designer

Feb 2021 - January 2022

- Gathering required insights to UX design by doing primary research with local shopkeepers, enhancing user flow, and creating delivery strategy.
- UX design for multi-platform Android, iOS, and web, performed user testing, competitor Analysis, Interviewed stakeholders,

SKILLS

- Prototyping
- Wireframing
- Iterative design process
- Data driven design solutions
- Agile UX methodologies
- User interviews
- A/B testing
- Competitor analysis
- Card sorting
- Heatmap Analysis
- Icon design
- Motion graphics
- Accessibility design

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Managed the entire iOS releatively cycle independently.
- Led overall development of chatbot reduced 30% customers calls.
- MVP quality delivery under 3 months, to understand product market fit.
- Revamped post-payment user flow, leading to a 15% reduction in drop rates.

TECHNICAL

- Figma
- Sketch
- Protopie
- Photoshop
- Azure
- Miro

- Created persona's, developed prototypes.
- Understand customer journey for onboarding flow, increasing overall user onboarding by 30%.
- Collaborated with the product manager and the front end engineering team to ensure a MVP quality delivery under 3 months.

Vyom, New delhi - Visual Design Architect

May 2019 - July 2020

 3D prototypes and presentations for architecture projects, engaging stakeholders with immersive visuals. Demonstrated user empathy through user interactions, enhancing designs accordingly. leadership and communication skills by doing design presentations.

Tradewill Interiors, Gurugram - Assistant Architect

May 2018 - April 2019

 Designed and supervised an institutional building in Gwalior, ensuring a user-centric approach. Produced presentation drawings and construction-ready plans, incorporating principles for optimal functionality.

Sanju Bose Landscape consultant, New delhi - Visual Design Architect

May 2017 - April 2018

Led presentations with design teams to various stakeholders.
Created 3D and 2D prototypes and walkthroughs to showcase the envisioned experiences.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Architecture (Honors), Kurukshetra University

August 2011 - September 2016

Spatial (Augmented reality) UX/UI Design certification, Designerrs

March 2023 - July 2023

UX/UI Design certification, Designwings

September 2020 - January 2021

- After effects
- Illustrator
- HTML and CSS
- Sketchup 3D
- Adobe Aero

LANGUAGE

- Hindi
- English

INTEREST

- Badminton
- Trekking
- Augmented Reality

PROVEN EXPERTISE

- Rapid iteration
- User testing
- Aligning business objectives
- Stakeholder workshops
- Process Improvement
- Feedback solicitation
- Visual storytelling
- Customer Journey mapping
- Storyboarding
- Stakeholder presentation
- Creating PRD's
- Creating user journeys